Prajna Paramita Dash (1) Featured

Software Developer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Apache Tomcat, Hibernate, Eclipse, Jenkins, ¡Query, MySQL, CSS



Current Designation: Information Technology Analyst Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

Current Company: Infosys Limited Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bhubaneshwar Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electrical]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Apache

Tomcat, Hibernate, Eclipse, Jenkins, jQuery, MySQL, Apache ant

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Software Developer at Infosys having 4 years of experience(Nov 2016-Till Date) in the field of Application Development, leveraging various technologies such as:

Java, SpringMVC, Spring Batch.

Hibernate, REST web services, JDBC, JQuery.

Well-rounded technical background with superior competency in developing Multi-Tiered Multi-user Web based Enterprise Applications using J2EE technology stack.

Research and Development: - Have done a poc (proof of concept) in java language (using jdk version 1.8) for migrating postgres database (including all tables, procedures, views, sequences) to oracle database.

Continuous Integration & Deployment of various application modules using TFS (Team Foundation Server).

Work Experience

Infosys Limited as Information Technology Analyst Nov 2016 to Till Date

I am working as a Technology Analyst at Infosys.

I am having 4 years of experience in the field of java development. I have worked on java, J2EE, spring framework, Hibernate framework, jQuery, SQL using Apache Tomcat, Apache Tomee,Oracle Weblogic server.

Infosys as Software Developer

Nov 2016 to Dec 2020

Client: Western Union Financial Services

Duration: Dec 2018- Nov 2020

Environment: Java, SpringMVC, Spring Batch, REST Function: Reconcilation of Transaction Systems

Description:

It is a unified reconciliation solution enabling financial institutions to automate and centralize reconciliations across various lines of businesses in one single platform.

Data capture: supports 16 different file formats(xls, xlsx, csv etc)

Matching: multi-level and multi-way matching with capability to apply tolerance, sign, netting, pattern etc.

Operations: Force match, auto match, split, merge etc.

Reporting: Transactions report, Feed Data Report, Recon Summary report, user Report etc.

Admin: Access Control, Environment Setup, License Management etc.

& Responsibilities:

Participated in discussions with consultants in requirements gathering and analysis in Pre-analysis phase.

Contributed in development, bug fixing and unit-testing.

Deployment of EAR files in SIT, UAT and Production servers.

Worked on Enhancement of new business logic and coding of different types of business requirements both at front end

and backend level.

Client: Citi

Duration: Sep 2017-Oct 18

Environment: Java, Oracle, Sybase, UNIX

Roles & Responsibilities:

Contributed in developing an application to book and manage appointments for bank customers. Migrated Sybase database version 11 to 15 and functional id remediation for Oracle database.

Unit Testing.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical) from Biju Patnaik University of Technology (BPUT) in 2016

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations Associate

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2020 Architect associate

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2020 Developer associate

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Hibernate, Web services (REST), JSON	
Java, J2EE, JDBC, CSS, Oracle,PostgreSQL	
XML, JSP, JQuery, Shellscripting	
Apache Tomcat, Windows, Linux, Eclipse	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Odia				

Projects

Project Title: Infosys Transaction Reconciliation System

Client: Western Union

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2018 - Jan 2021

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: It is a Western union financial services banking project.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname = e42f49575c0846d726da40da1741179f5858085318115c145514430e0b...

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time